VADIM BRODSKY WEB DEVELOPER + DESIGNER

+1 (519) 721-2856 vadim@vadimbrodsky.com

VadimBrodsky.com linkedin.com/in/vbrodsky github.com/VadimBrodsky

7 Settlers Dr. Kitchener ON, Canada N2E 2L7

PORTFOLIO

A sample of my design and development work can be found on my website: vadimbrodsky.com

PROFILE

Prolific web professional with over 8 years design and 4 years of development experience for the web. Accomplished in all aspects of the web development process; strategy, wire-framing, conceptual design, development, deployment, testing, SEO and performance optimization. Passionate about pushing the boundaries of the web, using and learning the latest technologies to solve challenging problems. Eager in finding the "Right" solution to a problem while evaluating the needs and tradeoffs of any alternative.

SKILLS

- Deep knowledge of modern front-end web technologies; HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript, as applied to the web browser, mobile devices and native clients.
- Creative, adept at developing full featured designs for digital and print mediums using Adobe CS Suite and Sketch, with special emphasis to typography and usability.
- Strategic in approach to any problem, keen on discovering the trade-offs and finding the most efficient way to achieve the goals of the user and the business.
- Experienced with back-end server technologies including CMS platforms, web application frameworks and third-party API integrations.
- Team player, love to collaborate with others to gain new insights and outlook for work.
 Familiar with Agile, Design Thinking, Design Sprint and SCRUM methodologies.

EXPERIENCE

Partner / Digital Strategist, Crankworks Creative, Kitchener ON — 2012–Present

- · Lead the agency's all digital and web development efforts and services.
- Instrumental in transitioning the company to a digital-first agency, driving more than 60% of the agency's revenues from digital work.
- Designed and developed numerous websites, web-applications and digital campaigns for high profile companies in the Waterloo Region and Canada ranging from startups, non-for-profits to enterprises.
- Collaborated on development of marketing strategies and UX best practices.

Magazine Designer, Craig Kelman & Associates, Winnipeg MB — 2011–2012

- Designed, art directed and produced more than 40 issues of leading US and Canadian industry magazines.
- Developed interactive rich media PDF publications, optimized for iPad and mobile.
- Managed monthly email newsletters that reached tens of thousands contacts.

Graphic Designer & Layout Artist, Nygård International, Winnipeg MB — 2009–2011

- Designed promotional material for a fashion company with international reach, including; newspaper ads, catalogues, books, flyers and postcards.
- Engaged in all stages of the fashion marketing process, including art direction, photoshoots, timeline planning, design, vendor negotiation and production.
- Developed collateral for all elements of the Nygard Fashion Retail stores.
- Created digital and print media including retail marketing materials, direct-mail promotions, email promotions, web marketing and mass media newspaper marketing.

Vadim Brodsky 1 of 2

VADIM BRODSKY WEB DEVELOPER + DESIGNER

+1 (519) 721-2856 vadim@vadimbrodsky.com

VadimBrodsky.com linkedin.com/in/vbrodsky github.com/VadimBrodsky

7 Settlers Dr. Kitchener ON, Canada N2E 2L7

PORTFOLIO

A sample of my design and development work can be found on my website: vadimbrodsky.com

Freelance Designer/Developer, Vadim Brodsky Design, Winnipeg MB — 2008-present

- Designed user interface mock-ups and assets for Android and iPhone applications.
- Built small to medium size websites with Wordpress CMS integration.
- Produced numerous designs and marketing projects including; branding, collateral, posters, stationary, flyers, direct-mail ads, publications, invitations and display signs.

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

The landscape of modern web development is constantly shifting, I believe in order to stay current one must always learn and continue developing.

University of Manitoba, Winnipeg MB — BFA Honours in Graphic Design, 2009

Udemy, Online Course — JavaScript: Understanding the Weird Parts, 2014

Udemy, Online Course — Complete JavaScript: From Fundamental to Functional, 2015

Tealeaf Academy, Online Course — Introduction to Ruby and Web Development, 2015

Pragmatic Studio, Online Course — Ruby on Rails Level 1/2, 2016

Thoughtbot Upcase, Online Course — Intermediate Ruby on Rails, 2016

Thoughtbot Upcase, Online Course — Test-Driven Rails, 2016

FrontEnd Masters, Online Course — JavaScript the Good Parts, 2016

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Design - Deep knowledge of design techniques, principles and tools: Responsive Design, Mobile First Design, User Centred Design, UI/UX Design, Wireframes, High / Low fidelity prototypes, Styletiles, Adobe Creative Suite, Sketch App, OmiGraffle.

Markup Languages - Experienced in the many ways of generating semantic web markup: HTML, XHTML, HAML, Jade, Liquid, ERB, Twig, Moustache, JSON, YAML, Markdown, SVG.

Style Authoring - Proficient in creating component based maintainable stylesheets: CSS3, SASS, Less, BEM, SMACSS, OOCSS, PostCSS, Compass, Bootstrap, Foundation.

Client-Side Programming - Knowledgeable in modern browser web development: JavaScript (ES5, ES2015), CoffeeScript, jQuery, NPM, Grunt, Gulp, React, Vue, Angular.

Server Programming - Experienced with server technologies in Ruby, JavaScript, PHP: Application frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Express.
Content management systems: Wordpress, Ghost, Craft, Jekyll, Middleman.
Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite.

Tooling and Workflow: Strong advocate of good tooling and workflows: Test Driven Development (MiniTest, RSpec, Capybara, Jasmine), Version Control (Git, Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket), Agile Development, PAAS (Heroku, Amazon AWS), VIM, Atom.

AWARDS

Signature Award (2012) - Advertising Association of Winnipeg, Winnipeg MB

References are available upon request.

Vadim Brodsky 2 of 2